DAKOTA ADAMS

dakota@dakotaadams.tech

503-298-8788 604 N Williams Ave Sioux Falls SD 57104

www.dakotaadams.tech

Skills

- Training Individuals
- Monitoring performances
- Troubleshooting
- $\\ \bigcirc \ Communication \ skills$
- Inspecting equipment
- © Customer service

Self-driven, motivated and a hard worker. Ability to prepare instructional material and deliver said material in an understandable manner. Proven skill in problem solving and professionalism. I was a heavy equipment and diesel mechanic for 10 years. It was a great career, but had begun to take a toll on my physical health. Learned a lot about hard work, time management and variable control techniques. I am now looking to forward my life in a new direction and am very excited about pushing myself in a new field. Thank you very much for your time.

Work History

U.S. Army 2015 - 2017

Senior mechanic

 Key/ Security handler, Tool inventory, Services and unscheduled maintenance

Halliburton 2017 - 2020 Mechanical Technician 1

- Services and unscheduled maintenance.
 - Cross trained individuals on new pieces of equipment using lesson plans that were understandable. Resulted in an increase in production and diversity in employees.

R + L Carriers 2020 - 2024

Foreman, Mechanic

- Truck, trailer, forklift and electric pallet jack mechanic.
- Designated to repair numerous vehicles. Was able to resolve issues by identifying the problem, then applying proper troubleshooting procedures. Solved all issues and maintained 100% vehicle dependability.
- © Created and maintained reports on all equipment and delivered the reports throughout the company ensuring fast, safe and smooth operations.
- Familiar with web based ticketing systems as that is what was used to report issues with equipment. Followed up on repairs and kept detailed logs of any issues and resolutions.
- Trained new personnel on equipment and the maintenance procedures for that equipment using prepared hands-on instruction. Resulted in an increase of the quality of work and the dependability of personnel. 100% pass rate on instructions

Studying

Python HTML CSS JavaScript

Hobbies

Computer building Guitar Video Games

<u>Links</u> <u>GitHub</u> dakotaadams.tech

Education

Astoria High-School 2013